All right, we are going to go from one
damn good guest to another damn good
guest. The man himself, John Keryaku.
>> Hey there.
>> How you doing, man? You're doing okay?
>> I'm doing very well, thanks. How are
you?
>> I'm doing fine. I'm doing okay. John
Kyaku, he's a former CIA officer,
author, speaker. His books include the
CIA Insiders Guide to Iran and The
Reluctant Spy. You can also find John on
his show. John, what is the name of that
show? Because you do
>> got two. I have one with Ted Raw called
Deep Program and the other one I do it's
more of a of a long form interview
format called uh Deep Focus
>> both on YouTube and Rumble.
>> You also
are traveling to give speeches.
>> Yeah. Um I'm in a hiatus right now and
we're going to start right back up uh in
the Western United States in December.
>> Okay. Very cool. Very cool. John, thank
you for joining me. I um I've started a
new tact of trying to write down
questions because it's well the problem
is like I usually like to have a
conversation with my guests.
>> Yeah.
>> And usually the questions are a guide
just in case there's a lull or something
like that. But when you're trying to
name a video, it is very difficult to
name a video. I struggle. I spend hours
trying to name videos and always feel
unfulfilled
at the end of the process. So, I'm
trying to name it, but that's inside
baseball. That's too much information.
Um, I'm I'm curious on something.
I think you made the point.
Well, let me just ask the question. What
is the CIA doing in Ukraine?
>> Well, by all accounts, uh, the CIA is
doing everything in Ukraine. Um, you
know, I I I'll admit to you that I've
been out of the CIA for quite some time
now, but but I'm still in touch with
people in those circles and they say
that the CIA is effectively running the
Ukrainian uh intelligence service. Um,
not just advising, but either approving
or disproving of operations. They're in
charge of of training both in Ukraine
and bringing Ukrainian intelligence
officers back to the United States to
train them here. So the keep in mind
that the CIA is not a policy um agency.
It's a policy support agency. And so
they they serve at the pleasure of the
president. And until the president says
we're leaving Ukraine, their job is to
provide everything they can possibly
provide. And that's where they are right
now.
>> So they are still the president's men.
>> Oh yeah. Without any question. And we
saw that I don't want to get, you know,
off the off the topic without you
leading me there, but um that's why we
saw last week 37 intelligence officers
fired. Uh there are no civil service
protections at the CIA because the CIA
serves at the pleasure of the president.
And so they do literally what the
president tells them to do.
So when people say stuff like um Trump
could do X or Y, but the CIA as a
monolith or as an organization doesn't
want that is that
>> well that's that's different in that
they can slow roll a president and just
you know ignore him, but they're they're
always at risk then of being fired.
There's no there they can't there's no
like panel that they can go to within
the civil service to say hey I was
illegitimately fired and uh you know the
president doesn't have the right to fire
me because of the civil service act of
19 whatever it was. They don't get those
kind of of um of protections.
So you know we're talking about one of
one of two things
as as far as the deep state goes. if
they get an order that they don't like,
they can sort of just move so slowly
that they can delay it as long as, you
know, until the president is no longer
present anymore. But in a case like
Ukraine where there's a where there's a
hot war taking place, they do as they're
told. Interesting. So, it's not the CIA
has a point of view and the CIA is
pushing back on Donald Trump in some
capacity of trying to in the way. It's
not that. It's all things been equal.
you will function there and you will do
the job for the entire duration of that
war until I pull you out from doing the
job.
>> Yeah. It was like the Iraq war, Jamarl,
the the second one where
the the the battle lines internally were
were clearly drawn. It was the pro-war
factions were the National Security
Council, the Office of the Vice
President, and the Office of the
Secretary of Defense. the anti-Iraq war
um organizations were the CIA, the State
Department, and the Joint Chiefs of
Staff. And it was because the CIA had
been single single-mindedly focused on
finding and killing Osama bin Laden.
They didn't want to be distracted by
going into some unnecessary war in Iraq.
They wanted to stay in Afghanistan and
and destroy al-Qaeda. But the policy
decision had been made and they were
told, "You're going to fall into line."
and they fell into line
>> on a daily basis. When you were at the
CIA, what did your job description look
like? I'm trying to get an idea on what
is the day in the life of a CIA spook
like what do like and for that matter
the same thing in Ukraine. They get up
in the morning, brush their teeth, get
breakfast, go to an office,
what like what is that?
>> It varies widely. um let's say during
the Iraq war. During the Iraq war, I was
the executive assistant to the CIA's
deputy director for operations. And so
our job was to prosecute the Iraq war.
And so, yeah, get up every morning 2:45
a.m., which was tough, man. It took me a
good three weeks to get used to that
kind of schedule. 2:45. I'm at my desk
by, you know, 4:00, 3:45.
And um I start going through the 10,000
cables that had come in overnight.
I whittle those down to between five and
10 that were important enough for the
director and the deputy director to uh
to hear. And um and then I wait until uh
sorry there's a mosquito that is no
longer alive. Um and then I wait for the
for the deputy director to come in. I
brief the all of the deputy directors at
7 o'clock. I brief the director of the
CIA at 7:30.
And then I start my day uh I mean I've
already worked half a day but I start my
you know the rest of my day which was
coordinating with the state department
with the defense department with the
office of the vice president. Um
answering presidential requests, sending
cables to the field, answering responses
from the field. Um you make a quick trip
to New York to talk to the United
Nations, the the CIA contingent at the
United Nations. you make a sometimes a
quick trip to London or to Kurdistan or
wherever um just to make sure people
have the weapons they need, people have
the equipment they need, they have
secure communications that they need,
and then you get the odd the odd
request. I got a I got a request from
Vice President Cheney one time and he
wanted to know what the what the longest
um air strip in northern Iraq was made
of.
>> Oh yeah. And I was like what? So nobody
in operations knew. They were like what?
And I I kept saying it's from Cheney.
Like Cheney specifically wants to know.
I said I I don't know the answer. So, I
ended up having to um to enlist the uh
the CIA librarian
uh and she said, "I can find this out."
>> And within 24 hours, she told me exactly
what it was made of and what the mix
consisted of and it was this much, you
know, concrete and this much I don't
know what. And so I wrote this memo and
I said here's and the reason why they
wanted to do that is because they wanted
to fly in tanks
>> and they wanted to know if if the runway
was solid enough to handle the weight of
a plane carrying two tanks landed on it.
>> Wow.
>> So every day it was something different.
Now when I was in counterterrorism it
was different still. Uh, I'd go into
work every morning at 7 and either I
would always start my day by reading the
cables that had come in overnight and
that usually took a couple of hours. But
then my boss would come up to me and
say, "Can you brief this group today?
Can you fly to Cairo this afternoon? Can
you, you know, brief the director on XYZ
program? Can you go to the State
Department and get them off our backs?"
You know, that kind of thing. Every this
is what I this is what I love the most
about the CIA is that every single day
was something completely different from
the day before. That's what kept me
engaged.
>> Does the president know what is
happening on the ground in regards in
relation to the CIA or is it just an
order is given and they just follow the
order as understood?
>> It it depends on the president. So
George HW Bush absolutely yes. He had
such a deep
love of intelligence, having been the
director of central intelligence
himself.
>> That's right.
>> That he wanted to know every single
detail, every detail. And so he was
briefed constantly, six days a week.
>> Um, Bill Clinton didn't give two shits
about the CIA or what it was.
>> He was briefed twice in his eight years
as president.
>> So what was the CIA doing? They were
just like, how does that work? How they
just went rogue?
>> He would give these overarching orders
and then trust uh Al Gore to implement
them. So Gore was briefed all the time.
Clinton
Clinton wouldn't, you know, Jim Woolsey,
who was Clinton's first CIA director, um
once famously said that Clinton wouldn't
know who he was if they bumped into each
other in a room.
his own CIA director. And then of course
after Clinton was Bush, Bush, I mean
really it was Cheney that ran the
country. So
Bush was pretty well aware. Cheney was
intimately dangerously involved. And
then uh and then Obama was deeply
involved. Trump didn't give a about
intelligence.
>> So he doesn't know what's going on. I
mean this is basically Trump get
basically status quo whatever that means
then you think wow if the CIA wasn't in
Ukraine
what would happen would it collapse I
mean is there any device edifice could
MI6 replace what the CIA is doing?
>> No not on a not on a paramilitary
training basis. Um,
you know, if if the if the goal were to
recruit spies to steal secrets, which is
what the CIA originally was supposed to
do, sure, they could be replaced by any
number of services. And um, but what
what the CIA is training them in is is
paramilitary operations.
So, I suppose you could
>> Oh, okay.
>> Yeah. I mean,
yeah, SAS could do it. um which which is
British special forces. The French could
probably do it if they were so inclined.
The Israelis definitely could do it, but
they're bogged down.
>> Yeah.
>> Um you know, honestly, Jamar, I don't
think there would be that much of a
difference if the CIA weren't there
anymore.
>> Really?
>> Yeah. Because I think that for all
intents and purposes, the war is winding
down. It's a stalemate. Uh we've all
said from the very very beginning that
if there's going to be peace, it's going
to be with the proviso that the that the
Ukrainians seed territory.
And um I I still think that's the case.
I think that's how
>> I'm sorry to interrupt. It doesn't seem
like a stalemate. I mean, the Russians
are making severe advances. And I mean
if you look at the battle map I I watch
battle map daily and the channels that
effectively go over what is taking place
in the movements even the Ukrainian
channels are freaking out because there
seems to be a flanking operation over
Laviance creremators what is it constant
>> sure what I'm saying is that if if the
original Russian goal were to was to
take out the uh Ukrainian leadership and
to threaten Keev
They're not really doing that anymore. I
think the Russians are solidly secure in
the Russian the ethnic Russian areas of
eastern Ukraine. Um certainly in Crimea
and the Ukrainians are going to lose
those territories.
>> Yes.
>> They just have to accept it. If there's
going to be peace, they're going to have
to seed this stuff to the Russians.
>> Ah, but there's the rub. As you point
out, the CIA is training paramilitaries.
Yes. And you have to ask, what are those
paramilitaries for?
>> Yeah.
>> Is it with the thought of making the
Russians?
>> Yeah. It's like It's like the great
wolves. It's for guerrilla warfare.
>> Exactly. Making the Russians.
>> Yeah. Exactly.
>> On Ukraine and then effectively using
guerrilla war in order to bog them down
for like a decade. That's what it seems
like.
>> I think that's exactly what the point
is. Yes.
>> Because otherwise I don't know what the
Europeans are doing.
um they seem Why doesn't Trump walk?
Doesn't he know that or does he get
that? There was there was a quote that
came out from the Atlantic and it says,
"In recent days, Trump has privately
complained that his high-profile
diplomacy has produced no results." I
love this, right? Because for the last
several months, I've been saying stuff
like
the Europeans seems to either be
delusional or they're trying to bog the
Russians down with this idea that real
war for 10 years. Trump seemed to
believe if this is true that
>> well, I can get these sides to come
together. I'm the dealmaker. I can make
a deal.
>> Right.
>> Which is what makes him so angry that
the Russians are just doing what he's
telling them to do.
>> And the Europeans.
>> Yeah. And the Europeans. Right. Yes.
Yes, because he's like Zalinski needs to
be more flexible. I have no control over
the Russians. You're the person I have
control over you. You're the one that's
losing the war with us also. Right. He
says um in recent days, Donald Trump has
completed uh privately complained that
high-profile diplomacy has produced no
results. Some officials close to the
White House told the magazine he has
directed quote some frustration unquote
at Zilinsky and the EU for being
unrealistic in demand saying Ukraine
would need to give up some territories
to end the conflict. The source claimed
quote he just wants this over with. It
almost doesn't matter how unquote a
senior official said.
>> I accept that to be true because that's
what I thought was true. He's he's sick
of this war.
>> He wants it over with.
>> He wants it over. My question to you is
why doesn't he just walk? He could walk.
He could tell the CIA, "Hey, we're out.
No more intelligence. No more weapons.
I'm not selling European uh Europeans.
No more weapons. I'm out. All of your
horrible people. I'm done. I'm Trump. Go
to my golf course." Yeah,
>> he could do that.
>> Yeah, he
>> My question is why?
>> I think for two reasons. Number one, it
would make him look weak.
>> He would go down in history as the
president who lost Ukraine.
>> Number one. Number two, he's the grand
dealmaker. Yeah,
>> he wants to make that deal. Well,
actually, and there's a third reason,
and we all know what it is. He
desperately wants to win the Nobel Peace
Prize. Everybody's talking about it,
right? He negotiated the deal or force
the deal between India and Pakistan,
between Congo and Rwanda, between
Thailand and Cambodia.
If he could bring a peace deal between
the Russians and the Ukrainians, he
really believes Palestine aside, he
really believes he would be competitive
for the Nobel Peace Prize. And he's
furious that Barack Obama won the No
Nobel Peace Prize without deserving it.
>> He wants to prove that he's a better
president at bringing that big peace
deal.
>> Yeah. I mean, but
I don't think what he fully gets is the
Russians are going to keep going.
They're not going to stop.
>> Yeah, I think he underestimated Russian
resolve.
>> But I guess my point is Ukraine is
either going to collapse or he's going
to get a deal. And if the Europeans just
going to be obsinant because their plan
is a guerilla war later on, backed by
the CIA's training of guerrillas,
>> then ultimately it will fail. and it
will fail in his watch either way.
>> Yeah.
>> So whether he walks
>> and gets blamed or whether he stays and
it fails, he's still gonna get blamed
for it.
>> That's why he needs a deal where both
sides agree to lay down their arms,
right? And and I think that he's
particularly upset because he really
believed that if he could talk the
Ukrainians into just giving up the
territory whether they like it or not,
the Russians would say, "Thank you,
President Trump. That deal will take."
And that's not at all what happened.
>> Yeah.
>> I think that's why he was so frustrated
coming out of Anchorage.
That was supposed to be the deal that
the grand dealmaker from the art of the
deal uh was gonna make,
>> but the Europeans said, "No, not good
enough."
>> Yeah, but Zalinsky was never going to
accept that either though.
>> Could be forced to accept it and Putin
can't be forced to accept anything.
>> Agreed. I do agree with you on that.
Providing Zalinski doesn't go rogue and
go hugging the Europeans. Like see
because from my point of view power that
Trump has at his disposal is walking
>> and as you point out he doesn't want to
do that
>> and it seems like the Europeans knows
it's almost like if I had a nuclear
bomb.
>> Yeah.
>> And I'm like hey don't make me use my
nuke but you know I'm not using my nuke.
>> Of course which is
>> like
>> Yeah. It's that
>> Yeah. Um, I saw an interview that you
did where you pointed out that the CIA
doesn't trust MSAD. Is that true
>> at all?
>> Why?
>> Oh my god.
>> They seem to be the most they're the
most moral spy service in the world,
John.
>> Oh yeah. They follow all the rules of
international law.
>> Yeah.
>> No, forgive my language, Jamar, but the
CIA hates Mossad because they're all
dicks.
You know, cooperating on intelligence is
one thing. A political decision was made
many years ago during the at the start
of the Nixon administration that we're
gonna we're gonna help the Israelis in
any way possible. We we guarantee
Israeli security.
>> Okay.
>> But be that as it may, the Israelis
continue to spy on the United States
actively recruiting American citizens to
steal defense secrets for them.
>> And they're just dicks in the way they
treat CIA officers.
>> That's really an example. I need an
example.
>> Yeah, I'll give you the same example I I
I mentioned on these other podcasts. Um
I had um two friends. We all sat
together at the CIA and in 1993 all
three of us went into Arabic training. I
went to Bahrain and my colleagues got
married and went to Jerusalem. Now, they
were both declared to the Israeli
Mossad, meaning the Mossad knew them as
CIA officers. The station chief took
them to Mossad and introduced them and
said, "You know my officers.
Um, they're not here to spy. They're
both analysts." Uh, the husband is going
to go to the university and study
Arabic. The wife is going to work in the
station just collecting biographical
information on on Palestinian leaders.
No threat to you guys. So
the ambassador had a a welcome party for
them at at the residence in Tel Aviv.
And when they got back to their house in
Jerusalem, uh somebody had rearranged
all their living room furniture while
they were gone. Now, that's just a dick
move. But it's like, okay, all right,
you guys can break into our house and do
whatever you want. We get it.
Fast forward to Christmas. The
ambassador has a big Christmas party.
They go to the Christmas party.
>> They come back to their house and um
people had taken shits in all of their
toilets and left it un
>> Oh, that's so gross.
>> Yeah,
>> that's so gross.
>> that's just gross. It's awful. And then
when they were getting ready to leave,
the ambassador had a farewell party for
them. And when they got back to their
house, the dog was under the dining room
table and it was whimpering because
someone had cut off its tail and wrapped
the stump in gauze and medical tape.
And I I had other CIA friends who were
declared to the Israelis. they would go
to uh Jerusalem to have liaison meetings
with uh the Israelis. And one of them
went in December, decided to go to the
old city and and do all of his Christmas
shopping. And then um just before he
left for the airport, somebody went into
his hotel room and stole every one of
the presents.
Like why do you do stuff like that? And
then the the station chief has to go to
the Mossad and say, "Look, stop screwing
around with my people. It's rude. It's
bad for relations." And they're like,
"Okay, okay." And then they'll back off
for a year or two. And then they start
doing it again. And they do it just to
screw with us, not for any any other
reason. No other service does that. No
other service.
>> Does America spy on Israel?
>> Absolutely not.
>> Why not? It's a hard and fast policy.
>> Why?
>> Because Apac says not to.
>> Are you serious, John?
>> Really, that's what it comes down to. It
It would be bad politics.
>> They spy on us.
>> Yeah, they do. Actively
actively spy on us.
>> It's the CIA.
>> They spy on everybody.
>> Yeah. Not on the Israelis.
>> Not even with a wink and a nod.
>> No. Doesn't happen,
>> John. That's mind-blowing.
>> It's awful. It's a terrible policy.
>> That is mind-blowing. I can't believe
that that's the entire world.
>> You know what, I was on I was on a panel
uh recently uh with Pierce Morgan.
Pierce Morgan held this panel and and it
included um Scott Horton, who is one of
the most brilliant
>> people I've ever engaged with on these
issues. Scott and I were on the one side
and the other side was Alan Dersowitz
and
uh General Danny Ayalam who was the head
of Mossad. And I told I told them what I
just told you. And I said, "The Israelis
are actively spying on uh on the United
States." And Pierce said, "Uh, General
Ayelam, is that is that true?" And he
goes,
"No, no, no."
and he said, "Well, what about Jonathan
Pard?"
And uh the general says, "Well, when
Pard got caught, that's when the prime
minister ordered us to stop spying on
the United States." That was 1985.
And I said, "That's funny because in
1990,
I got a briefing from the director of
security at the CIA saying that that
Israel was one of the most active
countries engaged in espionage against
the United States in the whole world."
And uh and Pierce says, "General, is
that true?" And he just goes,
"No comment.
It's rational." I mean, they need to
know where the US's head is, right? I
mean, but I'm saying it sucks. I can't
believe that CIA has done this even.
Wow, that's amazing to me.
>> And let me add one one thing about Pard,
too. Pard, by the way, is running for
the Knesset right now as an independent.
He announced his candidate. We don't
know when the election's going to be,
but he said in the next election, he's
running for the Israeli Knesset as an
independent. But Pard gave the Israelis
top secret
military and targeting information
that we had collected against the Soviet
Union. He gave it to the Israelis. The
Israelis then gave it to the Soviets
in exchange for a couple of plain loads
of Russian Jews. And then the Soviets
used it to shut down our sources. Are
you serious?
>> This was what this is what the courts
call grave damage to the national
security.
>> So it got those people killed in the
Soviet Union.
>> Yeah. People were executed for that
>> and the US still is like
>> we're in a great relationship.
>> All right.
>> Yeah.
>> What condition is Israel in right now?
Are they overextended?
>> I believe that they are. And I think one
of the things that we are under
underestimating in the American media is
the degree to which Israeli citizens are
now objecting to ongoing military
operations. You know, there was a
demonstration in Tel Aviv the other day
that was several hundred,000 people.
It's it was gigantic. Israel doesn't
have that many people.
>> It's only what 7.8 million.
>> That's exactly right. People are are
tired of being called up, reserve units
called up constantly to go to Gaza and
fight. They're tired of the expense.
They're tired of the deprivation.
They're embarrassed by the crimes
against humanity and war crimes that the
Israelis are committing and they want an
end to this thing. Now, I will admit to
you, unfortunately, that that's still a
minority view in in uh Israel, but it's
growing.
So, okay. So, if you were still an
analyst and you had to get an assessment
of what was taking place in regards to
Gaza, what would that assessment be?
Would it be we can carry this on and
could because they're still extending
into Lebanon? They're still extending
into Syria.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> They're still going with this idea of we
have our moment to create our greater
Israel project. So, that's what we're
going to do. We're going to create
greater Israel. Like that still seems to
be the mindset of the government with
the thinking that when all of this is
over, when all of these people are
murdered or kicked out, when we've taken
all of this territory, the country will,
you know, be something different,
something new, and everybody will
forgive what has taken place. I mean,
what what would be your assessment of
what has taken place on the ground in
regards to,
I guess, their capability of continuing
to go this route? I I think that the
Israeli government really believes that
it can expel every Palestinian starting
in Gaza and once Gaza is pacified it can
move they can move the the Israelis can
move to uh the West Bank where these
operations are still ongoing you know in
places like Janine
>> right
>> outside of Bethlehem
um they I think they really believe in
the concept of a greater Israel. Even if
it takes another hundred years or 200
years, I think they really believe that
they can expel every single Palestinian
and take all the land because they know
there's not going to be push back from
the United States. They don't care about
what any other country says, but I think
that they really believe that there
won't be push back from the United
States and they're going to continue on
with this policy.
>> Speaking of that, and what time is what
time is it?
Okay, we have a few minutes, couple of
minutes. Um, Russia has moved its
ambassadors out of the embassy.
>> The United States has moved troops out
of Iran, uh, out of out of Iraq.
>> Effectively, seemingly something is in
the air. Like, these countries seemingly
know something. Now, Israel does have a
relationship with both. It's very
possible that they gave full warning to
both.
>> Yeah. I haven't seen battleships move
into the area, which is key.
>> That's the key. That was one of the
lessons, the most important lessons I
learned at the CIA is if you want to
know if there's going to be a real war,
not just little pinpick strikes one at
the other. A real war, watch naval
moves.
And when I say naval moves, I mean
carrier battle groups. And you're right,
we're not moving carrier battle groups.
Not yet, anyway. Okay. I mean there
there are three that are in the region,
but we prosecuted the first Gulf War,
for example, with six carrier battle
groups. We had three or four carrier
battle groups for the second Iraq war.
And right now, we're not really moving
anything anywhere. They're just normal,
you know, maneuvers. One is in uh the
Arabian Sea and then it's replaced by
another one that's coming from the
Pacific. and the one that was in the
Arabian Sea is going back to San Diego.
So, if we were preparing for an honest
to god hot war, we would be moving large
numbers of warships to the region and
we're not doing that yet.
>> Then why is the US pulling out troops
from Iraq? I mean, it seems like Israel
is preparing for a
>> war. Or it could it could be a couple of
things. It could be um a result of talks
with the Iraqis because we we have been
in these ongoing talks with the Iraqis
with the Iraqis for a number of years
now to draw down our um troop numbers.
>> Yes.
>> Or it could be just regular scheduled
turnover.
>> Okay. I mean, but the Russian embassy
thing also is a little weird.
>> Yeah.
>> And both of these things happening
simultaneously.
>> And dad missiles effectively being added
to Israel's arsenal. They've been
getting loads hand over fists.
>> Yeah,
>> it seems like they're preparing to
strike Iran.
>> Well, Freda Parcy certainly thinks so.
Freda Parcy wrote a wrote a Substack uh
two weeks ago, two and a half weeks ago,
predicting that Israel would attack Iran
again before the end of the month. Um
Treata Parsey of course at um
at the where is Trita? At the is he at
the Hoover Institute? Anyway, Trina
Percy is one of the the foremost
thinkers on on this issue out there in
the Western world. Um, so if if he says
there's going to be a war, I would have
to put money on the fact that there is
going to be a war. But here we are on
the the 29th and it hasn't happened yet.
Not to say it can't. Not to say that
it's not going to be the first week of
September or the first week of October.
>> No. But I think if I had to bet money,
I'd say, yeah, there there are going to
be hostilities again. Yes.
>> Will the US back Israel? Because all
things been equal.
>> Yeah, of course.
>> So,
>> and I have to say, you know, if if I
were if I were Donald Trump, I would
think, you know, these Israelis are
embarrassing me because we keep telling
them, you know, we want to talk to the
Iranians and every time they bomb Iran,
the Iranians cancel the talks. And now
the Iranians are saying they're not
going to be talks. And then the Iranians
are saying they're going to pull out
from the NPT.
>> Yep.
>> Well, if I were the president of Iran, I
would pull out of the NPT.
>> They should.
>> What good has the NPT done for me if I'm
the Israelis aren't members? They
haven't exceeded to the NPT. So why
should Iran?
>> No. Agreed.
>> If the Israelis have nuclear weapons and
they're pointed at Iran,
>> how do the Iranians protect themselves?
The only way you can protect yourself is
to develop your own nuclear weapons.
>> Yep. That's a rational argument, John.
This is not about rationality. It's
about power.
>> Yeah.
>> John, thank you for this. I really I
really appreciate it. Your knowledge of
this stuff is so fascinating to me just
because of the experience and the life
that you've lived.
>> And so it's um
>> we don't know what goes on behind the
veil. And in some sense, you give us a
peak behind the veil. One day I went I
saw you on the UFO channel. Oh man. I
was like, "Oh my god."
>> Oh yeah. Oh, I forgot about that. That
was fun. Actually, I enjoyed that.
>> I'm gonna have to pick your brain on
that one day. Um because I would imagine
you may have some fascinating insights.
But thank you for this, man. John
Keryaku. John Keryaku is former CIA
officer, author, and speaker. His books
include the CIA insiders guide to uh the
Iran crisis and the reluctant spy. You
can follow John on Twitter, John
Kuryaku. You can learn more about him at
johncuryaku.com.
And you can find him on I just wrote
that thing down. Un what is the name of
it, John?
>> Oh, we've got uh deep program and deep
focus
>> and deep focus. I'm going to write it
into the thing. Thank you for this, man.
You be safe. Okay,
>> you too, buddy. Bye-bye.
>> Bye-bye. All right, John Kyaku, always
enjoy